[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
[Spring of The Blade]
[Episode 2]
The ceremony is complete.
Congratulations, Fourth Lady,
on returning to the clan.
I know that, given my lowly status,
I am not worthy of making my father
set aside his official duties
and return home.
But I really wish
I could serve him a cup of tea
as his daughter
to show my affection and concern.
There's nothing wrong
with your filial piety.
But with honored guests here,
it's inappropriate for you
to kneel all the time.
Indeed.
As beautiful as she is,
it would be a pity to ruin her knees.
Who is this?
- It must be Lord Yan from the capital.
-Lord Yan.
-Greetings, Your Lordship.
This must be the Fourth Lady
of the Xie family.
I heard you were missing for years,
but a fire brought news of you.
You truly are blessed by God.
You really took advantage of the fire
to return home safely.
Qingyuan,
we have a distinguished guest.
Stand up and greet him.
Be careful, lady.
I am Xie Qingyuan.
Greetings, Lord Yan.
You know my name?
What?
Have we met before?
I saw you have an imposing appearance
which far outshone
that of ordinary people,
so I ventured a guess.
If I am wrong,
please forgive me, Your Lordship.
You are not wrong.
You have a sharp eye, Fourth Lady.
Could you read my face
and tell
how many days I can survive in Hengtang?
Qingyuan,
put away your little tricks
and speak properly.
Can't you see what occasion it is today?
Since you are one of the Xie family now,
you must learn our rules.
[Xie Residence of Hengtang]
The Xie Residence is quite lively today.
I heard they brought
their Fourth Lady back
just in order to ward off evil.
The patriarch of the Xie family,
Lord Xie Shu,
is stationed at the Northern Frontier
all year round
and rarely returns home.
It's such a big event
as his own daughter's return
to the clan,
yet he didn't even come back.
It's normal he didn't.
You madams probably don't know.
About this Fourth Lady,
who returned today,
her birth mother
once killed someone.
Killed someone?
Everyone knows the Third Lady, Qingrong,
is listed under the name
of the Head Madam, Madam Hu.
But her birth mother, Concubine Xia,
was killed
by the birth mother of this Fourth Lady,
who just returned.
This incident caused
quite a stir back then.
From now on,
there will be no peaceful days for sure.
If I were Lord Xie,
I would also prefer to stay
at the frontier for some peace and quiet.
Nonsense.
Alright, alright.
We are guests.
Stop gossiping about the hosts.
Madam Hu has arrived!
[Mei Yinghua, Lord Xie's Second Concubine]
Second Madam,
the ceremony is over now.
[Liuhua Courtyard]
The Old Madam is
receiving guests in the front hall.
Are you really not going to take a look?
What is there to look at?
The harmonious grandmother
and granddaughter
are enjoying family happiness.
They've never
cared about my thoughts anyway.
Wouldn't I just be
making myself miserable by going?
I won't go.
Our Eldest Lady
has the same personality as her mother.
She likes peace and quiet
and doesn't talk much.
No one knows where she's hiding right now.
Mother.
This is my daughter, Qingru,
the second child.
Greetings, madams.
These are March Red lychees
just sent from Danzhou
for you to have a taste.
What a wonderful girl.
You raised her very well.
Qingru, you may leave.
Yes.
Madam Hu, you've nurtured her well
into a proper heiress.
Indeed.
When I visited
the Xie Residence last time,
the place was a mess,
burned down by a fire.
Now it has been restored
so fast and elegantly.
Seems like the repairs went well.
Yes, of course!
It cost over ten thousand taels of silver
to restore it to its original state.
Even the crabapple tree in the courtyard
was replaced
with an identical one from outside.
This wine is
refreshing and delicious.
Good wine.
Speaking of this wine,
it's certainly not a treasure.
Despite the ordinary wine,
the cups I chose for it are not bad.
It's genuine Yaozhou celadon,
the first batch from the old kiln.
Second Young Master,
you're quite generous.
Having this Yaozhou celadon
at the ancestry reclaiming banquet
just shows how wealthy the Xie family is.
Yes, of course!
Our Xie family is famous in Hengtang.
There are hundreds, if not thousands,
of rare treasures in our home!
Zhengjun!
Grandmother.
Zhengjun,
you're drunk.
Lord Yan,
don't listen to his nonsense.
Second Madam,
Second Young Master caused trouble again
and annoyed the Old Madam.
Is Zhengjun
an idiot?
The wealthy families in Hengtang are all
keeping a low profile
to survive the winter.
He's the only one
showing off our wealth outside,
like he wants others
to target our Xie family.
Anyway, since this pool of water is
already muddy,
let's stir it up even worse.
Qingrong is not
a generous girl, is she?
Go point her in a direction.
How can
our Zhengjun bear the blame
alone?
Yes.
Third Sister.
Don't call me sister.
As the daughter of a murderer,
born bad,
do you deserve
to step into the Xie Residence?
Third Sister,
whether you want it or not,
whether you're willing or not,
as long as I'm still surnamed Xie,
we have to live under the same roof.
I don't want to make an enemy of you.
Please be magnanimous, Third Sister.
Grandmother is still waiting for me.
I'll take my leave.
Do you think I'm afraid of you
just because you brought up the Old Madam?
Be magnanimous?
When your mother used euphorbia
to kill my mother,
did she ever anticipate
that one day her daughter
would have to pay with her life?
Today is your return
and ancestor worship ceremony.
Guess
who the sacrifice is.
Just before the ceremony,
Grandmother gave you this longevity lock.
This longevity lock
was specially purified
with incense ash from the altar
just in order to ward off evil.
Do you know why you were left outside
for so many years
without anyone looking for you,
but they chose
to put you in the genealogy now?
Because a concubine's daughter
born on the Ghost Festival
makes the best scapegoat.
You want a long life?
I want you to pay
with your life right now!
Qingrong!
What nonsense are you talking about?
Old Madam,
what brings you here?
If I didn't come looking for you,
how would I know someone
could be this audacious?
Yuejian,
take the Fourth Lady
to receive the distinguished guests.
Then go to Wuzhu Courtyard
and get the First Madam here.
Yes.
You,
come with me.
Penalty drink! Drink!
Penalty drink!
Lord Yan, you are so amazing.
It's yours.
Thank you, Lord Yan.
Qingyuan!
Fourth Lady,
you are the star of today's event.
Your second brother has drunk too much.
Why don't you
drink for him?
Okay!
Let Lord Yan check out
how extraordinarily smart Qingyuan is.
Pay with her life?
Scapegoat?
Have you ever
thought about the consequences
if the guests today hear what you said?
Grandmother,
the fact that I didn't kill her
on the spot just now
was already me
protecting the Xie family's reputation.
Everything started because of her mother.
Just let Jin
harm her own daughter!
How dare you quibble?
I have repeatedly ordered
not to mention the past grievances.
Do my words fall on deaf ears?
Then did my mother
deserve to die unjustly?
I heard Qingrong caused trouble.
Qingrong,
I'm not trying to scold you.
But you've been
with the Head Madam for so long,
and how can you still be so reckless?
Old Madam.
Concubine Mei, you're right.
I failed to discipline her well.
I will be stricter with her from now on.
You are so passionate
about criticizing others,
but you are no better, either.
Yan Rui was ordered by His Majesty
to root out corruption for disaster relief.
Our Xie family is in a sensitive position.
And your silly son
kept talking nonsense,
letting others catch us out.
How did you educate him?
In short,
from now on in this residence,
everyone must watch their words and deeds.
You must not make mistakes like today's.
-Yes.
The object Lord Yan hid
should be round in shape
and contain liquid—
lamp oil.
Let me open it!
Look.
It really is.
Qingyuan, you are amazing!
I will take my leave first.
-Stop there.
-Qingyuan.
Ladies just all
play hard to get like this.
Your Lordship,
please mind your behavior.
Are you angry?
Are you thinking of
splashing that lamp oil on me
and setting me on fire?
I wouldn't dare.
You wouldn't dare to commit arson,
or you wouldn't dare to bet with me?
Your Lordship,
I just guessed blindly just now.
I would never dare to compete with you.
Your Lordship, please
don't make things difficult for others.
I just like to beat tough guys.
What are you afraid of?
Qingyuan,
bet with him.
Then, Fourth Lady, please
guess what's in my sachet
and how much it's worth.
Let's see if it matches your answer.
Lord Yan is back.
-Lord Yan.
-Cheers.
-Come on.
-Let's drink.
Cheers.
The thing in the sachet is
the most valuable treasure in the world.
It's priceless.
You are wrong, lady.
This is just a pile
of moldy millet.
How is it priceless?
Grain is the common people's foundation.
His Majesty has warned the officials
to value grain over gold and jade.
After millet is cooked,
it can not only fill the stomach,
but long-term storage can also be
a preparation for emergencies.
Even moldy millet
is still a priceless treasure
for starving people.
Therefore, I think this answer is correct.
Fourth Lady, you're really eloquent.
You can even talk up
this pile of rotten grain
as an invaluable treasure.
Then why don't you
come with me
to see how many of these treasures
your Xie family's farm has?
Be careful.
-Why did Lord Yan bring up the farm?
-I'm okay.
Is it related
to the recent corruption case?
Keep it down.
Lord Yan,
you are really well-informed.
The Xie family's farm
does indeed
have some old grain stored.
But
Zhengjun traded good grain
for them.
As long as we can,
we won't let people eat moldy grain.
Qingyuan is right.
Grain may be cheap,
but it concerns the people's livelihood,
making it more precious than gold.
Given the disaster
Hengtang is suffering from right now,
on behalf of the Xie family,
I'd like to donate
100 dan of grain.
100 dan?
That's a lot.
It's enough to feed 200 households
for 3 months.
You are so righteous, Old Madam.
I'm deeply impressed.
Then I thank you in advance, Old Madam.
Fourth Lady, it seems that you are
indeed the Xie family's mascot.
I'm flattered.
It's all thanks to the Xie family's
profound ancestral blessings
and the Old Madam's grace.
♪ Lest he prove untrue
and leave us heartbroken ♪
The southern opera is performed tonight
♪ Today Zhang Xie rides through
the streets in triumph ♪
to welcome you into the family.
♪ But he's short of helping hands ♪
♪ Let's go lend him ours ♪
Back then, this song was
♪ The ghosts will bear the sedan chair ♪
your mother's favorite, too.
♪ The gods will blow the trumpets ♪
Yan Rui visited us today.
If the Xie family
had gotten involved
in the corruption case,
it would've definitely caused us
grave damage
and disastrous consequences.
Fortunately, you
stayed composed in the face of danger
and acted appropriately.
You handled it very well.
I just used some small tricks.
I don't deserve your praise, Grandmother.
I am already deeply grateful
that you don't blame me
for embarrassing the Xie family.
When I was little, I lived a lonely,
difficult life away from the Xie Residence,
growing up among the common folk.
My birth mother once made a grave mistake
and harmed the family.
Logically speaking, my background
is not worthy of the Xie family.
You didn't abandon me, Grandmother,
which allowed me
to enjoy today's blessings.
I cannot repay you enough
for this kindness.
From now on, I promise I will place
the Xie family above everything else.
I will give it my all
until the very end of my life.
Silly girl.
You call me Grandmother,
so we are family.
Since we are family,
we should let go of past grudges
and help each other.
As the saying goes,
a child is innocent
of their parents' crimes.
As long as I am in the Xie family,
I will never
let anyone make things difficult for you.
Thank you, Grandmother.
-Bravo!
Come on, Your Lordship,
let me pour you a drink.
Your Lordship,
I left the banquet quite early today.
I heard that you
gained a lot from the Xie family.
What?
Lord Wei, you want to raise the stakes?
That's perfect.
I was just worrying about
not having enough.
I wouldn't dare.
I was a bit reckless.
I thought
you wanted to use the Xie family
to investigate the corruption case.
I am here this time for disaster relief.
If it's not handled well,
it might irritate His Majesty.
So, for the food collection,
Lord Wei, please
pay more attention to it for me.
As for corruption,
I will just catch several people,
take them to the capital,
and consider it done.
My Lady, what are your plans now?
Firstly, gain the trust of the Old Madam.
And then investigate
my mother's unjust case.
No rush.
They will eventually know
I am the vengeful demon,
back to claim their lives.
You may go back first.
Yes.
Third Sister.
You are quite composed.
You already know
why the Xie family got you back,
and you're still not leaving?
Leave?
Where to?
Since I have been listed
in the Xie family's genealogy,
I am one of the Xies.
Of course, I should stay
in the Xie Residence
and take care of the Old Madam.
Do you think you can turn the tables
by clinging to the Old Madam?
Your Lordship, what are you looking at?
Lord Wei, please help me check
if the one standing on the bridge is
the Fourth Lady of the Xie family.
It is indeed the Fourth Lady.
No wonder she looks familiar.
She really tickles my fancy.
Since I've run into such a beauty,
please excuse me
for ending our chitchat here, Lord Wei.
Your Lordship, I'll leave you to it.
Listen,
even if you've been placed
in the genealogy,
it can't change the fact
that your mother is a murderer.
But I am a lady of the Xie family,
and that is also a fact.
So what else can you do?
Beat me,
scold me,
or make things difficult for me?
But this filial piety
won't bring any honor
to the late Fifth Madam.
Third Sister, your reluctance to let go
will only make
the Fifth Madam suffer
in the netherworld day after day,
unable to reincarnate.
Then go to hell right now!
Die and pay for my mother's death!
So it's the two ladies of the Xie family.
How did you two end up fighting?
Someone fell into the water!
Tell me
your purpose for entering the Xie family.
If I hand over the evidence of your arson
to the Xie family,
do you think
they will believe you, a fake lady,
or me, an official?
My Lord.
My Lord!
Wake up, My Lord!
My Lord,
are you alright?
Who saved me?
It's...
It's the Fourth Lady who saved you.
Where is the estate manager?
The estate manager...
is dead.
Come on.
-Hurry!
-Move!
-Move! Make way!
-Someone died.
My Lord,
we've searched him.
The ledger is gone.
Who is this dead man?
I don't know.
The estate manager brought
the item to me as agreed.
It seemed like I was the target,
but actually,
someone tried to stop him
from approaching me,
even resorting to murder to silence him.
Someone fell into the water!
The ledger.
Who on earth was it?
Mother.
Please don't worry too much.
Didn't the official
who came back with Qingrong
already say
that the Fourth Lady
and Lord Yan are not injured?
Lord Yan is a high official
from the capital.
There must be many people
keeping an eye on him.
It's fortunate that they aren't hurt.
But an unmarried girl
fell into the water
with an unrelated man.
If this gets out,
people will inevitably
suspect a secret rendezvous.
I'm afraid that's much worse
than an injury.
Qingyuan just arrived
at the Xie Residence,
and she's already caused such a stir.
We must keep a close eye on her
from now on
to prevent her from tarnishing
our Xie family's reputation.
After such a big incident,
where are you going, lady?
Your Lordship,
although I saved your life,
you don't need to appreciate it too much.
If it were anyone else,
I would have saved them all the same.
But, Your Lordship, you really have
poor swimming skills.
You should practice more
when you are free.
A wet-haired beauty
fleeing under the moon,
how interesting.
You're far more adept
at hooking up with women
than investigating cases.
Is that a compliment?
If so, I will accept it.
Fourth Lady, did you know
that the person who just died
is your Xie family's estate manager?
Your Lordship,
I have just arrived at the Xie Residence,
so I am not quite familiar
with these relations.
It's fine if you don't know.
Then please take a look, lady.
Is this sachet
something from the Xie family?
It should be
my Second Brother's sachet.
Oh, dear.
We found on the corpse the belonging
of your Xie family's Second Young Master.
This makes things tricky.
I've got no choice but to investigate
according to the law.
Your Lordship,
the deceased
died on the shore.
He didn't fall into the water
before he died.
This sachet is so wet.
Perhaps it fell into the water
with someone else?
You are so smart, Fourth Lady.
Why didn't I think
of drying it before taking it out?
Your Lordship,
are you openly telling me
that you are framing him?
Aren't you afraid I'll report it
to the authorities?
No.
Because you taught me, Fourth Lady,
that if I am guilty,
you will be my accomplice.
Don't worry,
I will definitely confess
and bring you down with me.
Your Lordship,
I wonder
when I offended you.
During the game
at the ancestry reclaiming banquet,
you deliberately made things difficult
for me with stale millet.
Didn't I
do you a favor in return?
Isn't the Xie family's 100 dan of grain
enough to please you?
Or
do you want more?
You knew exactly why I came,
yet you still played along with my act.
Wasn't it just to establish your prestige
in the Xie family
and prove your worth as the Fourth Lady?
Can we even settle the score between us?
Are there any good people
in the Xie family in your eyes?
And now you're playing the role
of a devoted family member?
Was that big fire
really just to make the Xie family
lose some money?
Fourth Lady,
some lies are just lies.
Don't fool yourself.
Then what do you want, Your Lordship?
I want you to watch a good show
of the Xie family with me.
Then you have got
the wrong person, Your Lordship.
I don't understand shows.
Right, you understand chess.
You are meticulous
and advance step by step.
But don't forget,
if a chess player
cannot even see her own moves clearly,
she can only be a chess piece—a pawn.
But I don't need
another player on my chessboard.
Is it that you don't need one,
or you don't want one?
We walk different paths,
so we're not meant to work together.
Please don't force me, Your Lordship.
I just want to force you.
I don't care if you're willing or not.
I will definitely
take control of your game.
Qingrong and Qingyuan
are both listed under my name.
Such an incident happened
due to my failure in discipline.
When Qingyuan comes back,
I promise I will strictly discipline her.
Right now,
no matter what happened,
the Fourth Lady falling into the water
with an unrelated man
will surely cause a scandal
if word gets out.
Zhengjun.
Hurry and bring the Fourth Lady back.
If she stays out overnight,
things will escalate.
Clouds are gathering
on the horizon right now.
Our family can't afford
any more incidents.
Go now.
Okay, okay.
I'll go. I'm going.
Lord Yan has arrived!
Isn't she back now?
Lord Yan.
Qingyuan
really doesn't know her place.
How could she let you, Lord Yan,
escort her back personally?
It's a matter of great importance.
Of course I must escort her.
Escorting her is one thing.
But Lord Yan, why did you barge in
with a troop of soldiers at midnight?
If this gets out,
other people
might think the Xie family
has committed a serious crime.
Indeed.
I don't know either.
Whether your Xie family is guilty or not
depends on how I investigate.
Why do you say that, Your Lordship?
Lord Yan,
did Xie Qingyuan cause any trouble
and get escorted back by you as a culprit?
Qingru.
The Fourth Lady
did encounter some trouble.
She was almost
pushed into the water
by the Third Lady of your Xie family.
I am the witness.
The Fourth Lady saved my life underwater.
It is only right
for me to seek justice for her.
That's not true, Grandmother.
I...
I just missed my mother too much,
thinking of the past grievances.
I didn't mean to do it.
I just lost my mind for a moment.
Grandmother.
You fool.
How many times have I told you?
Don't make a fuss
over baseless rumors.
But you never listen!
Nanny Rong.
Yes, Old Madam.
Take the Third Lady away
and lock her in the ancestral hall.
Have her copy Buddhist scriptures
to reflect on her actions as a penalty.
Yes, Old Madam.
Third Lady,
please come with me.
Lord Yan,
there has been a lot of misunderstanding.
There is no grudge
between my Third Sister and me.
We just lost control of the aim
when we were playing around.
I'm the one to blame.
I didn't stand steady.
Such a trivial matter
shouldn't bother you.
Lord Yan.
Qingrong and Qingyuan
offended you today.
It was indeed improper.
It's truly my failure as a mother
to discipline them.
I'd like
to apologize to you here, Your Lordship.
Please forgive us.
It doesn't matter.
I have no interest in the domestic affairs
of your Xie family.
Let's talk about something serious.
The Xie family's estate manager
is dead.
Lord Yan,
this is a weighty matter.
Please
move to the reception hall
to discuss it in detail.
About tonight's murder case,
the Fourth Lady saw it with her own eyes.
The dead estate manager
was clutching
your Second Young Master's sachet.
If I didn't keep Fourth Lady as a witness,
wouldn't it be a baseless slander
against
your Second Young Master's reputation?
Fourth Lady.
It was dark, and my eyesight is poor.
I was also very scared.
I
really didn't see clearly.
Perhaps
there was a mistake.
Our Xie family has been blessed
by His Majesty's grace
and stuck to our duties for years.
We would never dare
to overstep our bounds.
Lord Yan, you should not
accuse anyone
of the grave crime of murder easily.
Of course,
I'm well aware of it.
Without evidence,
I definitely wouldn't cause trouble
for no reason.
Nor would I
frame an innocent person randomly.
Right,
Fourth Lady?
Your Lordship,
my Second Brother is a kind person.
Old Madam is also compassionate.
In the face of disaster,
the Xie family still thought of
how to relieve the people.
With such kind hearts,
how could they kill anyone?
There must be
some misunderstanding here.
Then how on earth
did this sachet end up
in the deceased's hand?
Zhengjun is
too playful.
Usually,
visiting brothels
is a common thing for him.
In places of pleasure,
it's just common
to drop a sachet, right?
Is this Yunya tea?
It tastes really good.
It's even better than the tribute tea
in the capital.
You must be joking, Your Lordship.
Yunya tea
is nothing rare.
Tomorrow, I will
have someone send 2 baskets
to your residence.
You may not know this, Old Madam.
I am
worried about raising grain every day.
Now that there is another murder case,
how can I be in the mood to taste tea?
The Xie family's warehouse
still has a little surplus grain.
If it can solve your urgent problem,
Your Lordship,
it can be considered a meritorious deed.
are you satisfied with the result
of today's chess game?
Fourth Lady, you're quick-witted
and meticulous about every move.
You are actually more suitable
for playing chess than I am.
Your Lordship,
you just falsely claimed
to have a sachet as evidence,
forcing my grandmother
to give away the grain.
I didn't want to make an enemy of you,
so I played along with this lie.
Since you have already gotten
what you wanted,
why are you still pushing so hard?
How do you know that
grain is all I want?
No matter what you want, Your Lordship,
I
only implore you to show mercy
and stop getting me involved in this.
You want to escape?
No way.
There is a good saying
in the opera troupe—
once the music starts, the show
must not stop until it's finished.
With such a brilliant show,
how could I bear to let you
leave early?
I wonder if you've heard
about 2 sentences
in the "Kṣitigarbha Sutra," Your Lordship.
"All living beings
not liberated
have unfixed natures and minds.
Doing good or evil
depends on their circumstances."
Your show may be brilliant, Your Lordship,
but the risk is also high.
If good circumstances turn bad,
and good people turn evil,
wouldn't the losses
outweigh the gains for you?
Therefore,
Your Lordship,
you still need to choose carefully
and decide cautiously.
Don't let
an insignificant character like me
ruin
your carefully choreographed grand show.
By the way, Fourth Lady.
My cloak is priceless.
You must keep it well.
After all,
we have plenty of time ahead.
What he wants is not grain.
He has a hidden motive.
Could his target also be the Xie family?